Guide to the Pat Musick papers, 1943-2010.
Musick, Pat papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Pat Musick papers, 1943-2010.
6834
Patricia L., Musick 1926-
3.1 cubic foot.
Audio Recordings, Correspondence, Printed Materials, Publications
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes sketchbooks, production records, correspondence, exhibition catalogs, articles written by or about Musick.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Cornell University M.A. 1973, Ph.D. 1974.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes sketchbooks, production records, correspondence, exhibition catalogs, articles written by or about Musick, DVD's of interviews and art shows, listings of permanent acquisitions, permanent public installations, outdoor sculpture and site specific installations, solo exhibitions, honors awarded, reprints and reports about art therapy and art psychotherapy, audio cassettes of interviews and photographs.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Musick, Patricia L.,1926-; Cornell University--Alumni and alumnae.
Subjects:
Art therapy.; Women artists.; Sculptors; Artists
Form and Genre Terms:
Sketches.; Audiocassettes.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Biographical
Series II. Correspondence
Series III. Publications - by Musick and about Musick
Series IV. Exhibits
Series V. Sketchbooks, Drawings, Scrapbooks
Series VI. Audio Cassettes, Videos, CDs, DVDs, Photographs
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Biographical
  - Vitae and Biographies (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Artist Statements, 1980-1990s (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - PhD Dissertation - filmstrips, 1974 (Box 6)
  - Reunions - Santa Anna High School - Class of 1944, 1984; 1994 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - The Ariel- Santa Anna High School Yearbook, 1944 (Box 1)
  - Speeches, 1990-2001 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Jack Musick and Cornell Hall of Fame Induction and Dedication of Football Locker Room, 1986-2003 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Course Preparation-Kimball Union Academy, 1964-1966 (Box 5)
  - 3 Travel Memoirs-Italy, 1989,1995,1999 (Box 6)
  - Travel Memoirs-Spain, 1992 (Box 5)
  - Travel Memoirs, 2005 (Box 5)
- Series II. Correspondence
  - Correspondence, 1947-1970s (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1980s (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1990s-2012 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence with Professor Bink Noll - including SONY recording tape of Bink's Reading, and cassette tape of his Memorial Service on November 12, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence with Pat Maloney, High School Friend, 1990s (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence from Family (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence from Caryn Chase (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence from Alan Mathios, 2013 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Series III. Publications
  - Publications and Journal Articles by Musick (Box 1)
  - Magazine Articles about Musick (Box 1)
  - "Stone Songs on the Trail of Tears" - Book by Pat Musick (Box 1)
  - "No New Thing Under the Sun: One Artist's Chosen Journey" - Book by Pat Musick (Box 1)
  - "Artists of the Spirit" by Mary Carroll Nelson - Book discussing Musick (Box 1)
  - "Around the World in 84 Days" - Book about Jerry Carr (Box 1)
  - Life Book (Box 5)
  - "The Sourcebook of Architecture and Interior Art 16" - Includes Pat's Sculptures, 2001 (Box 6)
  - Article "A Comparison of the Similarities and Differences Between the Works of Eva Hesse and Pat Musick" - by graduate student, Ronny Myers, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Series IV. Exhibits
  - Various Exhibit Booklets (Box 1)
  - Exhibit Brochures, 1987-1991 (Box 1)
  - Exhibit Brochures, 2001-2008 (Box 1)
  - Ozark Woodland Sculpture Garden, 2000-2006 (Box 1)
  - Exhibit Catalog-"Past Presence-A Circle of Women's Visions", 1987 (Box 5)
  - Maya Angelou Inspired Exhibit Folder (Box 5)
  - Exhibit Catalog-Arkansas Exhibitions, "The Art", 1999 (Box 6)
- Series V. Sketchbooks, Drawings, Scrapbooks
  - Various Original Drawings and Designs, 1980s-1990s (Box 2)
  - Sketchbooks (Box 2)
  - "Pat Musick Chronicles," Scrapbook Documenting Art Career, 1943-1993 (Box 3)
  - "Pat Musick Chronicles," Scrapbook Documenting Art Career, 1994-1997 (Box 3)
  - "Pat Musick Chronicles," Scrapbook Documenting Art Career, 1998-2002 (Box 5)
  - "Pat Musick Chronicles," Scrapbook Documenting Art Career, 2003-2007 (Box 5)
  - Original Christmas Cards-done during Hanover years and miscellaneous art (Box 5)
  - Sketchbook (Box 6)
  - "Pat Musick Chronicles", 2008-2014 (Box 6)
- Series VI. Videos, CDs, DVDs,Photographs
  - Ms. Carr's Art Works - Japanese TV Videotape, 1983; V-5432 (Box 3)
  - "Trail of Tears" Dedication - news clip, n.d.; V-7097 (Box 6)
  - Arkansas Traveller, n.d.; V-7098 (Box 6)
  - Profile Fayetteville Artists - Open Channel, n.d.; V-7099 (Box 6)
  - Pat Musick Chronicles - Articles, Brochures, Announcements, 1963-1997; CD-726 (Box 4)
  - Musick Portraits, CD-727 (Box 4)
  - Pat Musick Vitae, 2003-2010; CD-728 (Box 4)
  - Pat Musick Archives - A Slides, CD-729 (Box 4)
  - Pat Musick Archives - B Slides, CD-730 (Box 4)
  - Production Records #1 - Pat Musick, CD-731 (Box 4)
  - Production Records #2 - Pat Musick, CD-732 (Box 4)
  - Production Records #3 - Pat Musick, CD-733 (Box 4)
  - Production Records #4 - Pat Musick, CD-734 (Box 4)
  - Maya Angelou Poem at Bill Clinton Inauguration - Accompanied Pat Musick "Shape of Her Words" Exhibit, DVD-596 (Box 4)
  - Crystal Bridges, Museum of American Art - Installation and Dedication - Images and Videos, May 2010; DVD-597 (Box 4)
  - TV Appearances and Video Tapes - Disc A, 1985-1999; DVD-598 (Box 4)
  - TV Appearances and Video Tapes - Disc B, 1981-1989; DVD-599 (Box 4)
  - TV Appearances and Video Tapes - Disc C, 1999-2002; DVD-600 (Box 4)
  - The Place Where They Cried Crystal Bridges - KFSM Channel 5, June 1, 2010; DVD-601 (Box 4)
  - The Arts Show - PEGTV Rutland Community Access, March 18, 2010; DVD-602 (Box 4)
  - The Arts Show with Mary Crowley, June 13, 2008; DVD-603 (Box 4)
  - Jack Musick: Recordings, DVD-604 (Box 4)
  - John Elmore Musick - Life and Family, DVD-605 (Box 4)
  - Southern Vermont Artscape, 2012; DVD-759 (Box 4)
  - Interviews on Audio Cassettes, Artists of the Spirit-Arkansas; October 1994 (Box 5)
  - Photos of Ronnie, 1978 (Box 5)
  - Photos from Florence, 1982 (Box 5)
  - Photos from Jack Musick Hall of Fame Induction (Box 5)
  - Photos from trip Pat took alone to Italy, Florence (Box 6)
  - Photos (3) of Pat Musick and Jerry Carr - Football Championship at the 40th Reunion, 2011 (Box 6, Folder 1)